

Contact Details:

Bangalore, India

(+91) 7077731777

ky bkdazs@amail.com

ABOUT ME

Managing a high-functioning, productive team of software developers, Managing the process and tooling for an agile development process, and also Collaborating effectively with cross-functional peers to deliver software on time and within budget. With 8+ years in backend software development, deep understanding of software architecture and infrastructure. 3+ years in team leading experience and 1+ years of experience in people management.

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

SOFT SKILL

COMMUNICATION
PROJECT MGMT
TEAM MGMT

BIJAYA KRISHNA DAS

Lead Engineer / Architect

EXPERIENCE

Solutions Architect

SIEMENS TECHNOLOGY (2022 - PRESENT)

Worked as a solution architect for Siemens Energy creating a single data lake, integrating several data sources and building a robust ETL data pipeline to populate data in realtime and to build solutions around the data lake on top of AWS tech stack.

Technical Lead

APPLIED MATERIAL INDIA PVT LTD (2019 - 2022)

Playing the role of architect and technical lead. Translate application storyboards and use cases into functional applications. Design, build, and maintain efficient, reusable, and reliable python code. Ensure the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of the applications. Identify bottlenecks and bugs, and devise solutions to these problems. Did the code fix production issues within a short time.

Technology Manager

UBER INDIA PVT LTD (Wipro Payroll) (2018 - 2019)

Delivered all projects on time and within forecasted budgets. Proven record of recruiting, developing, and retaining great talent, building dev teams. Managed a team of 6 engineers and was responsible for their mentorship, growth and job satisfaction. Provided Assistance to teams in Release & Deployments: Adherence to timelines, unit tests, and scope.

Senior Software Engineer

DRG ANALYTICS & INSIGHTS (2016 - 2018)

Developed numerous backend applications, in various roles starting from an individual contributor to project lead.

Senior Software Engineer

SOURCEBITS TECHNOLOGY (2014 - 2016)

Developed multiple backend web applications for different clients.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY	DEGREE	TIMELINE
BITS PILANI	M. Tech (CSE)	2018 - 2020
BPUT, ODISHA	B. Tech (CSE)	2008 - 2012
P. N COLLEGE	XI - XII	2005 - 2007
K. H. S	I - X	2005

OTHER SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, Golang, MySQL, Postgres, NoSQL, MongoDB, Docker (Basics), DevOps, Cloud Computing, Distributed Computing, Kubernetes (Basics), Ansible(Basics), GraphQL, GraphDB, SQL, Shell Scripting, GitHub, CI/CD, Angular, Reactjs(Basics), Node.Js, Linux, MSSQL, Redis, Flask, Data Analytics/Science (Brief Exposure), Blockchain (Learning), Agile, Scrum, Conflict Resolution, DS Algo, Software Architecture, Scalability, Availability, Java, Springboot(learning)

DOMAIN EXPERIENCE

1. Education, 2. Healthcare, 3. Transportation, 4. Service, 5. Ecommerce, 6. Finance, 7. Energy

PROJECTS

PROJECT NAME	COSI DATALAKE		
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK	
15	ARCHITECT	Python, AWS, Flask, Knowledge Graph, SPARQL	
DESCRIPTION	Designed and implemented a robust ETL pipeline framework low code platform to integrate several data sources and pump these data to a data lake based on knowledge graph, RDF, SPARQL.		

PROJECT NAME	Medley		
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK	
5	LEAD ENGINEER & ARCHITECT	Python, Serverless, AWS, Flask, Postgres, MSSQL	
DESCRIPTION	AMAT's middleware to fetch data from external and internal sources and store it in a centralized db.		

PROJECT NAME	Pathway Serverless 2.0	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
5	LEAD ENGINEER & ARCHITECT	Python, Serverless, AWS, Flask, Postgres, MSSQL
DESCRIPTION	A serverless application built on top of AWS Lambda to provide a set of REST APIs to frontend apps.	

PROJECT NAME	Legacy product support &	migration (Pathways, MSSQL DB, .NET Applications)
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK

5	LEAD ENGINEER & ARCHITECT	Python, Serverless, AWS, Flask, Postgres, MSSQL
DESCRIPTION	A set of AMT's legacy applications the	at are migrated to new serverless architecture and maintained

PROJECT NAME	UBER Onboarding & Offboarding System	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
6	ENGINEERING MANAGER	Python, Flask, MySQL, Reactjs, AWS
DESCRIPTION	Uber Onboarding and offboarding system of new & relieved employees (part of IAM application)	

PROJECT NAME	Uchat	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
6	ENGINEERING MANAGER	Python, Flask, MySQL, Reactjs, AWS
DESCRIPTION	Ubers enterprise chat application is a clone of slack.	

PROJECT NAME	Perks		
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK	
6	ENGINEERING MANAGER	Golang, MySQL, Reactjs, AWS	
DESCRIPTION	Uber's internal application to provide monthly credit to employees in Ubers App.		

PROJECT NAME	Social Analytics 1.0		
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK	
4	LEAD DEVELOPER	Python, Postgres, AWS	
DESCRIPTION	I am working on a product which will scrape and crawl data from various public forums and social networking sites and do analysis on them.		

PROJECT NAME	Cohort Generation Tool 1.0	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE TECH STACK	
3	LEAD DEVELOPER	Python, Postgres, AWS
DESCRIPTION	Developed a Big Data product to generate report and do cohort analysis on a 60 billion records approx. 100 TB of Data was managed spotlessly by this app.	

PROJECT NAME	Relay Data Pipeline	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
2	LEAD DEVELOPER	Python, Postgres, AWS

DESCRIPTION

https://www.linkedin	.com/in/krishx/	
DESCRIPTION	Developed and supported an inhouse ETL tool built using python which was scheduled and regularly scrape data from various open databases for healthcare.	
PROJECT NAME		Alerts 2.0
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
7	LEAD DEVELOPER	Python, Postgres, AWS
DESCRIPTION		ch would update our clients about updates on our drug er status as well as our analysts.
PROJECT NAME	Analytics 2.0	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
12+	LEAD DEVELOPER	Python, Postgres, AWS
DESCRIPTION	I was part of a team which developed a client specific analytics platform. I worked for a limited period only specific to a particular module called AMD.	
PROJECT NAME		Business Planning 1.0
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
5	Sr. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER	Python, Postgres, AWS
DESCRIPTION	Developed an application which was to handle business goals, objectives, analysis, targets of top pharma companies.	
PROJECT NAME		Merk Data Feed
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
3	Sr. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER	Python, Postgres, AWS
DESCRIPTION	Developed Data Feed Reports and automated the reports on regular intervals. After generating the report it would be automatically uploaded to a remote server.	
PROJECT NAME	Publisher 2.0	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
12+	Sr. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER	

PROJECT NAME	Publisher 1.0	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK

I was part of a team which developed some 200 custom websites for top pharma companies to provide formulary information. Also an upgrade to 1.0

12+	Sr. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER	
DESCRIPTION	· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	developed some 200 custom websites for top pharma ormulary information. First Version delivered to client.

PROJECT NAME	Todays Account 2.0	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE TECH STACK	
5	Sr. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER	
DESCRIPTION	I was part of a team which developed a data intensive application which was only to handle sales, leads, marketing, meetings of top pharma companies.	

PROJECT NAME	Validation Tool 1.0	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE TECH STACK	
2	Sr. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER	
DESCRIPTION	I had developed one application which was to validate the tier status and any changes in data requested by clients and the entire workflow.	

PROJECT NAME	Data Exports	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE TECH STACK	
5	Sr. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER	
DESCRIPTION	I was part of a team where we had to develop an application to automate various reporting workflow.it was a cloud based UI Tool.	

PROJECT NAME	Formulary Bot (Pioneered this Product)	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE TECH STACK	
3	PROJECT LEAD	Ruby, Ruby On Rails, Python, Postgres, NLTK, Scikit Learn
DESCRIPTION	I had developed an AI chatbot which was initial integrated with slack to be used by our analysts but later became a full-fledged product that was driven by voice and text.	

PROJECT NAME	Enterprise Portal	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE TECH STACK	
1	Sr. BACKEND DEVELOPER	Java Script, Node.js, MongoDB, AWS
DESCRIPTION	I had developed a project management tool for the company which was a replacement for SAP ERP solutions. Thereby saving millions of dollars for the company. Which had allocation, invoicing, inventory, leave, project milestone etc.	

PROJECT NAME	Momentum Machine
--------------	------------------

TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
10	Sr. BACKEND DEVELOPER	Java Script, Node.js, MySQL AWS
DESCRIPTION	l had developed this projec a hybrid app connectir	t for a burger making startup in silicon valley. Which was ng customer's orders with burger making machines.

PROJECT NAME	Genio	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE TECH STACK	
8	Sr. BACKEND DEVELOPER	Java Script, Node.js, MongoDB, AWS
DESCRIPTION	This app was developed for a silicon valley startup which was trying to imitate uber for service providers.	

PROJECT NAME	MoodBucket	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
4	Sr. DEVELOPER	Ruby, Ruby On Rails, MYSQL, AngularJs, HTML, CSS, AWS
DESCRIPTION	This iOS application was developed for a startup for collecting movie review from users. And providing various gifts.	

PROJECT NAME	iCareLife	
TEAM SIZE	DEVELOPER	TECH STACK
10	Sr. DEVELOPER	Ruby, Ruby On Rails, MySQL, AngularJs, HTML, CSS, AWS
DESCRIPTION	was part of a team which had developed a website for training and placement of individuals in informal economy such as drivers, maids etc.	

PROJECT NAME	Wptools	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
3	DEVELOPER	Ruby, Ruby On Rails, MySQL, AngularJs, HTML, CSS, AWS
DESCRIPTION	This was an enterprise application for the replacement of JIRA and other project management tools thereby saving a lot of bucks for the company.	

PROJECT NAME	Dmos	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
4	DEVELOPER	Ruby, Ruby On Rails, MySQL, AngularJs, HTML, CSS, AWS
DESCRIPTION	The purpose of the application was to refine the hiring process of that company by conducting an online test. I was part of the backend team to develop the RESTFUL API.	

PROJECT NAME	VJM Portal
--------------	------------

TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
1	DEVELOPER	PHP, Wordpress, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Cloud
DESCRIPTION	I had developed a news website which was basically a content management system based on PHP, HTML,CSS, JS VJM Portal	

PROJECT NAME	Instore-Asia	
TEAM SIZE	ROLE	TECH STACK
1	DEVELOPER	PHP, Codeigniter, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Cloud
DESCRIPTION	I had developed a mobile optimised website which was to take real-time votes for marketing and advertising to decide the winner or popularity.	